Markus Bodner

email: me@markusbodner.com · phone: +43 699 1900 14 94 · website: https://markusbodner.com

Full-stack software engineer with 12+ years of experience. Passion for coming up with simple innovative user interface designs and quality software solutions to solve user's needs. Always with an eye on performance and accessibility.

Experience

2014 - 2023

Self-Employed doing web, mobile & desktop development

Development and sale of software (web, mobile, desktop) and every duty required to keep things going: managing servers, transactional & bulk mailing, payment processing, app stores, marketing.

- Self-directed planing and execution for developing entire products
- Learning and implementing new technologies, tools, and programming languages
- Customer support

Sep. 2011 - Dec. 2013

Software Engineer, HELLA Sonnen- und Wetterschutztechnik

- Programming bill of materials of awnings for ERP by translating technical drawings and specifications.
- Direct collaboration with product development, sales, and production to guarantee smooth processing of orders.

Nov. 2010 - Aug. 2011

Process Technician, HELLA Sonnen- und Wetterschutztechnik

- Discovery and resolution of recurring manufacturing defects and issues.
- Optimization of production flow with production management and factory floor.
- Support for sales branches, field workers, and direct customers with regards to order status and prioritization.

Education

HTL Villach

"Reife- und Diplomprüfung" (Matura) with focus on software development and business management.

Programming Languages Elixir, Swift, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Objective-C, Dart, Java, C#

Databases Postgres, SQLite, Realm, SQL

Frameworks, APIs & Tools Phoenix Framework, Ansible, Docker, Git, Bash, Stripe, Paddle,

transactional & bulk email, nginx, Caddy, Xcode/iOS/macOS, NodeJS,

Photoshop

Languages German, English